>> Welcome everybody.
>> 欢迎大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
My name is Eric Tamura, and I am
我是 Eric Tamura
a manager on the file systems
是文件系统团队的一名经理
team primarily for iOS and our
我们团队主要负责 iOS
embedded devices, and I'll be
和嵌入式设备 我会
talking to you about what's new
向大家介绍 Apple File System
in Apple file system.
的一些新动向
I'll also be accompanied by
和我一起的
Pavel Sokolov, who's a manager
是 Pavel Sokolov  他也是
of the file systems team largely
文件系统团队的一名经理
for the Mac.
主要负责 Mac
So let's get started.
那么我们开始
So this presentation will
本场演示
roughly be divided into two
将大体分为
sections.
两个部分
I'll tell you a little bit more
我会向大家
about what's new for iOS as well
介绍一些 iOS
as tvOS, watchOS, and then Pavel
tvOS 和 watchOS 上的新内容  Pavel
will come up and tell you all
会在之后出场 向你们介绍
about what's new on macOS.
macOS 上的新内容
So let's jump right in.
那我们马上开始吧
So last year I got up on the
去年 我也在 WWDC
stage at this conference, and I
做了演讲
told all of you that Apple
告诉大家 Apple 从 2017 年起
[inaudible] Apple file system,
将要推出 Apple File System
as the default for all devices
作为所有设备的
starting in 2017, and we've
默认文件格式 并且
certainly done that.
我们确实做到了
So as of iOS 10.3 as well as our
所以 在 iOS 10.3
tvOS and watchOS analogs, all
以及同时推出的 tvOS 和 watchOS 中
devices have been migrated to
所有的设备都已转换到
APFS.
APFS 上
We'll tell you a little bit more
这一点稍后我们会
about that.
详细介绍
We'll talk a little bit more
我们还会介绍
about the conversion process,
转换过程
how did devices actually move
设备到底是如何
from HFS+ to APFS, and then a
从 HFS+ 转换到 APFS 上的
little bit on normalization and
以及 normalization（规范化）
case sensitivity, particularly
和区分大小写 尤其是
as it relates to iOS devices.
在 iOS 设备上
So let's talk about that
那么我们就来谈一下
conversion.
转换过程
So at this point, millions,
目前 数百万
literally hundreds of millions
确切地说是数亿
of devices have now been
设备已经
converted successfully to APFS.
成功转换到了 APFS
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So starting on iOS 10.3 as well
从 iOS 10.3
as tvOS and watchOS, Apple file
以及相应的 tvOS 和 watchOS 开始
system became the default.
Apple File System 成为了默认文件系统
We had millions of devices
已经有数百万设备
converted.
完成了转换
And one of the things you might
你们可能注意到
have realized that this update
此次更新
actually does free up some
确实释放了
storage for end users.
用户设备上的存储空间
In particular, there was space
尤其是释放了
previously occupied by the prior
之前的宗卷管理器
volume manager, lightweight
lightweight volume manager（轻量宗卷管理器）
volume manager, which is no
占用的空间 因为我们
longer needed, and we were able
不再需要它了 可以
to free up that space and give
释放这部分空间
it back to users.
把它还给用户
One of the other things is that
还有一件事情 那就是
starting in iOS 11, we are able
从 iOS 11 开始
to start taking advantage of the
我们可以充分利用
APFS capabilities in iOS and
iOS tvOS 和 watchOS 中
tvOS and watchOS.
AFPS 的功能了
Particularly iOS where iCloud
尤其是 iOS  因为
backup can now use Snapshots in
iCloud 备份可以使用快照
order to take a stable copy of
来稳定地备份
the file system and upload
文件系统 并上传到
everything to the Cloud without
云端 而不必
worrying about whether or not a
担心是否有某个过程
process might be modifying a
改变了某个文件
file and getting rights
或是让权限
intermingled.
含混不清
And finally we've been listening
最后 我们也听取了
to developer feedback in order
开发者的反馈
to improve and refine the file
来改进和完善
system and all the software that
文件系统 以及其他
we've been working on.
我们开发的软件
So let's talk a little bit about
那么 我们来简要介绍一下
that conversion process.
转换过程
So the APFS conversion occurs in
APFS 转换发生在
line during the update to iOS
升级到 iOS 10.3
10.3 and beyond.
和后续版本的过程中
So whether you're moving to iOS
所以 无论你是从此前版本
10.3, 10.3.2 or even iOS 11 from
升级到 10.3 10.3.2 甚至 iOS 11
some prior update, it will
你的文件系统
automatically get converted.
都会自动完成转换
And one of the reasons that we
我们能做到这一点
were able to do this so
如此成功的原因之一
successfully is that we actually
就是我们实际上
employed a dry run conversion
在 iOS 10.0 10.1 和 10.2 中
during iOS 10.0, 10.1, and 10.2
进行了试转换
and be able to track how the
因而能够追踪
health of our conversion process
我们的转换过程
was actually going.
是否足够完善
And we've also been monitoring
我们也一直关注
the health of the conversion
iOS 10.3 及后续版本升级中
during iOS 10.3 and beyond
转换过程是否完善
updates, and we've been watching
我们对此
that as well.
同样密切关注
Finally, we've been also looking
最后 我们也仔细分析了
at the numbers and statistics
我们关注的数字 数据
and everything that we're
和其他一切信息
watching and be able to improve
进而能够在 Mac 上
and refine the conversion on the
改进和完善
Mac as well.
转换过程
So sometimes an illustration can
有时 一张图
help make this easier to
往往胜过
understand, so I've got one
千言万语 这里也
here.
有一张
So let's assume that this
我们假设
rectangle represents the
这个长矩形代表
entirety of a block device and
一个完整的文件块
on the far left you'll notice
而在最左边 能看到
that there's and SB that really
有一个 SB
refers to the superblock or the
即 superblock（超级块）
HFS+ volume header.
同时也是 HFS+ 宗卷的卷头
Let's say for simplification we
简明起见
have three metadata regions that
我们有三个元数据区
report all the entirety of what
代表文件系统
the file system might be
追踪的一切信息
tracking, things like file
其中包括
names, time stamps, where the
文件名 时间戳
blocks actually live on disk,
以及磁盘上的文件块
and that we also have two
还有两个区域
regions labeled file data, and
标记为文件数据
if you recall during the
如果你还记得
conversion process the goal is
转换过程的目的
to only replace the metadata and
是仅仅替换元数据
not touch the file data.
而不触及文件数据
We want that to stay exactly
我们希望文件数据
where it is as if nothing had
能保持原样 就好像
happened to it.
从没有对它进行过操作
So the first thing that we're
所以我们首先要做的
going to do is identify exactly
就是找到
where the metadata is, and as
元数据的位置
we're walking through it we'll
同时 还要开始
start writing it into the free
将元数据写入
space of the HFS+ volume.
HFS+ 宗卷的可用空间
And what this gives us is crash
这样一来
protection and the ability to
可以防止系统崩溃
recover in the event that
并且能够尽快恢复
conversion doesn't actually
防止转换过程
succeed.
以失败告终
Now the metadata is identified.
一旦找到了元数据
We'll then start to write it out
接下来就要将它
to disk, and at this point, if
写入磁盘 此时
we were doing a dry-run
如果我们是在试转换
conversion, we'd end here.
那么整个过程就到此结束
If we're completing the process,
如果要完成这个过程
we will write the new superblock
我们就要写入新的超级块
on top of the old one, and now
并覆盖原有的超级块
we have an APFS volume.
这样就有了一个 APFS 宗卷
The final step is to simply
最后一步
remove the metadata that was
就是移除
previously occupied by the HFS+
包含 HFS+ 信息
content.
的元数据
We'll do that, and at this point
做到这一点
it's a completely converted APFS
这个宗卷就彻底转换到了
volume.
APFS 上
So now a quick word on Unicode.
再简单提一下 Unicode
So if you know anything about
如果你了解 Unicode
Unicode, you know there's
你应该知道
actually multiple variants, but
Unicode 有几种变体
for the purpose of discussion
但为方便讨论
here, I will only be referring
我只会提到其中两种
two really, which are NFC and
即 NFC 和
NFD, and these roughly
NFD  这二者
correspond to precomposed
大致对应着
characters versus decomposed
预作字符
characters.
和分解字符
And what this means is that you
这意味着
can actually store the same
你可以存储
character visually, the same
外观相同的字符
actually be stored multiple ways
可以用多种方式存储
depending on which form you're
取决于你使用的
using.
字符形式
Now prior to iOS 11, APFS stored
在 iOS 11 之前
file names as nonnormalized
AFPS 使用非规范化的 UTF-8
UTF-8, and what this means is
存储文件名 这意味着
that if you have a file with one
如果你有一个文件
representation versus the other,
名称有多种表示方式
they will actually be treated as
它们会在检索
different file names for the
创建和比较时
purposes of lookup and creation
被视作不同的
and comparison.
文件名
So let's give another example to
我们再举个例子
make this easier to understand.
方便大家理解
Let's say we have the character
比如说
n with tilde or [foreign
带腭音符号的 n
language] in Spanish.
也就是西班牙语中的 ñ
You can represent this as the
你可以将它表示为
Unicode hex f1 character.
Unicode 十六进制码的 F1
Alternatively, you can also
或者 你可以把它
store it as a decomposed
存储为分解字符
character in which the n is
也就是把 n
stored separately from the
和腭音符号
tilde.
分别存储
Now in this case, on the right
在这个例子中 右边的
the n and the tilde will be
n 和腭音符号
stored as two separate code
是作为两个代码点
points; however, they will be
分别存储的 然而
treated as having to be combined
系统会将它们
for the purposes of visually
按合并方式处理
representing that character on
以在屏幕上显示
your screen.
这个字符
So the problem is that even if
所以问题在于
the file system is taking care
即便文件系统
to treat these as separate,
能够将它们分别处理
that's not necessarily what the
系统的其他部分
rest of the system expects and
也不一定希望
interacts with.
以这种形式和它们互动
This might be well-defined
对于网络文件服务器
behavior for NFS; however, you
这可能再清楚不过 但
entire software stack from file
整套软件服务
system all the way up to
从文件系统一直到
foundation and above is able to
基础服务以上 都能
treat everything properly.
正确处理
So in order to rectify this,
所以 为了修正这一点
we're introducing two new
我们在 Apple File System 中
normalization schemes for Apple
引入了两种新的
file system.
规范化方案
We have a native scheme as well
一种是本地方案
as a runtime normalization
另一种是运行时
scheme.
方案
Now the native normalization
本地规范化方案
scheme is available in your high
已于本周早些时候发布的
Sierra beta that you got earlier
High Sierra beta 中提供
this week for case-sensitive
只能用于区分大小写
volumes only.
的宗卷
For case insensitive content,
对于不区分大小写的内容
Pavel will get up on stage in a
Pavel 稍后会上台
little bit and tell you all
并向大家
about that.
简单介绍
The native normalization is
本地规范化
coming soon for iOS 11 for erase
也将登陆 iOS 11
restores only.
只能用于抹掉数据恢复
This means if you plugged in the
这意味着 从 iOS 11 开始
phone or other device to iTunes
如果你将 iPhone 或其他设备
and did a restore to factory
连接到 iTunes
settings starting with iOS 11
并还原出厂设置
will automatically pick this up.
就会自动采用本地方案
However, we don't want anyone to
然而 我们不希望
have to erase install in order
只有抹掉数据
to get this behavior.
才能获得这项功能
So we're also introducing a new
所以我们也将引入
runtime normalization mechanism,
运行时规范化方案
and the runtime normalization
运行时规范化
will automatically convert
会自动在
between the NFC content versus
NFC 和
the NFD for the purposes of file
NFD 之间转换
comparison, being able to do
以实现文件比较 进而实现
lookups.
检索功能
If it doesn't find one, it will
如果找不到二者之一
automatically look up with the
便会自动寻找另一种
other to make sure that your app
以确保你的 App
doesn't receive an ENOENT
不会从文件系统中
[phonetic] error back from the
收到 ENOENT
file system.
错误
And a future update will
我们在未来会推出更新
automatically convert devices
自动转换使用
from whatever form they were in,
任何一种规范形式的设备
if they were already migrated
如果设备已经升级到了 iOS 10.3
starting in 10.3 or 10.3.2 to
或 10.3.2 完成了转换
the new form in a future update.
也能通过未来升级采用新的规范形式
So that's the update for iOS,
这就是关于 iOS 的新消息
and with that, I'm going to hand
至此 接下来
it off to Pavel, who is going to
交给 Pavel 让他来
tell you all about the Mac.
告诉你们关于 Mac 的消息
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
[ Background Noise ]
[ 背景噪音 ]
>> Good morning everyone.
>> 大家上午好
My name is Pavel Sokolov, and I
我是 Pavel Sokolov
manage file system team in
是 Apple 文件系统团队
Apple.
的一名经理
Today I'm going to talk to you
今天 我会介绍
about what's new in macOS with
macOS 有关 APFS
regards to APFS.
的新变化
Let's begin.
让我们开始
So first, I would like to talk
首先我想谈谈
to you about what features are
其中包含哪些特性
here just in case you missed the
以防你们没有听过
presentation from the previous
去年演示
year.
的内容
Important features that we
一些最重要的特性
have-- first of all, I would
包括 首先
like to remind you that APFS is
我想提醒大家 APFS
available to every
能够用于 Apple 支持的
Apple-supported platform.
所有平台
It works on iOS, tvOS, even on
能够用于 iOS tvOS 甚至是
your watch, and macOS, of
Apple Watch  当然还有
course.
macOS
One of the awesome features is
最了不起的一项特性
cloning.
就是文件复制
It allows you to do fast copies
你可以很快创建
of the files.
文件的副本
It employs our copy-on-write
它采用我们的
technology that also powers our
写入时复制技术 这项技术也用于
Snapshots.
快照功能
Snapshots allow you to take a
你可以使用快照功能
[inaudible] Snapshot of your
创建整个文件系统
file system, entire file system,
的快照
remember it's date, and later
记住创建时间
possibly return to it.
还可以恢复到某个快照
We will also natively support
我们也加入了对本地加密
encryption.
的支持
We have space sharing.
还有空间共享
I'm going to talk to you about
这一点稍后我会
that a little bit later, and we
多做介绍 我们还引入了
introduce defragmentation.
去碎片化
How will get to APFS you might
你可能会问 要如何才能
wonder?
获得 APFS
So let's talk a little bit about
那我们就先来
that.
谈谈这点
Actually, all you have to do is
实际上 你只需要
simply call a new macOS High
安装最新的 macOS High Sierra
Sierra and your system volume
你的系统宗卷
could automatically be converted
便会由安装器
by installer.
自动转换
In case you wonder what happens
至于其他宗卷
with other volumes, they are not
则不会被
going to be automatically
自动转换
converted, but you can still
但你仍然可以
manually do so.
手动转换
If you convert multiple volumes,
如果你要转换多个宗卷
the important point to remember
非常重要的一点是
after conversion each volume
转换过后 每个分卷
becomes APFS container.
都会变为 APFS 容器
I'm going to talk about that a
这一点稍后
little bit later.
我会讲到
And multiple containers do not
而多个容器间不会
share space.
共享空间
Space sharing is one of the most
空间共享是一项
important and awesome features
十分重要且令人惊叹的特性
that's going to save you space.
它可以节省你的磁盘空间
And we would like you to take
我们希望你能
advantage of that, and I can
充分利用这一点 我也会
show you how.
展示利用方法
You might wonder what volumes
你可能会问 我们支持
are supported, what we can
哪些宗卷 以及哪些
convert APFS.
能转换成 APFS 格式
We can convert HFS+ volumes,
我们可以转换 HFS+ 宗卷
CoreStorage, Fusion, and even
CoreStorage  Fusion  甚至是
FileVault encrypted.
FileVault 加密的磁盘
They all become APFS
都可以自动转换成
automatically.
APFS 格式
If you'd like to do a manual
如果你想手动
conversion of your existing
转换已有
volume, all you have to do is go
宗卷 只需要
to disk utility [inaudible],
打开 磁盘工具 App
right click on the volume,
右键点按分卷
select convert to APFS, and here
选择 转换至 APFS
you go.
就可以了
As I mentioned, if you do so,
我之前说过 这样一来
the volume becomes a container
这个宗卷会变成容器
and continues do not share
而容器无法共享
space.
空间
We would recommend if you have
如果你有多个分卷
multiple volumes and would like
又想要利用
to take advantage of that
这项功能
feature that you actually go and
我们推荐你
add volumes to the system
将分卷添加到
container and move your data
已有的容器
over.
再转移数据
Why space sharing is so
为什么空间共享
important and what's so good
如此重要 它又有
about it?
哪些优点
Let's talk a little bit about
我们就来
that.
大致谈一下
Here's the typical volume layout
如果你是一名开发者
that you might have as a
这是一种比较典型的
developer.
宗卷布局
You probably have multiple
你可能有多个
volumes, right?
宗卷 对吗
What's the deal with multiple
多个宗卷的问题在于
volumes is as you start running
如果某个宗卷
out of space in each of them,
空间不足
you might have a little bit of
你可能这里有一点
free space here, a little bit of
可用空间 那里有一点
free space there, but you do not
可用空间 但都不在
have enough in one single
同一个地方
location so when you try to copy
所以要复制文件的时候
your files, nothing you can do.
也无能为力
In APFS world, the container is
APFS 格式下 容器是
a partition on your volume, and
宗卷的一个分区
volumes share the free space of
各个宗卷共享容器的
that partition.
可用空间
So let's look at that picture.
我们看一下这张图
In a typical case, you would
一般情况下
have a GPT header, [inaudible]
会有一个 GPT 卷头  一个 EFI
service partition, and
服务分区
[inaudible] each volume is a
HFS 格式下 每个宗卷就是一个
partition.
分区
In APFS world, as I said, we
而在 APFS 格式下 像我说的
have eight containers of this
这个分区共有八个容器
partition and volume [inaudible]
两个宗卷
side of it.
也在其中
Let's say you want to fill up
比方说 你想
the space.
填满空间
As you can see in HFS you run
如你们所见 在 HFS 下
out.
没有空间了
In APFS, you still can use your
但在 APFS 下 你还有
free space and have your data
可用空间 可以存储
here.
数据
Let's explore the cloning.
接下来看一下复制
Cloning is [inaudible].
复制是一项了不起的特性
It allows you to make fast
你可以快速创建
copies of the files.
文件的副本
In this particular case, let's
这个例子中 我们
take a local [inaudible] file.
选取一些本地文件
It has a couple of blocks, and
它由一些文件块构成
traditionally if you copy a file
过去 要想复制文件
you have to copy the data over,
你要复制文件的数据
and that takes time.
这很花时间
Not only it takes time, it takes
不光花费时间 还会占用
space.
空间
In APFS, all we have to do is to
APFS 下 我们只需要
record the references to that
记录对这个文件的引用
file, remember where the file
记住文件的位置
is, and only your metadata is
只需复制
[inaudible].
元数据即可
It's also because it's fast and
这项功能很棒 因为过程很快
you don't waste space.
也不会浪费空间
You might wonder what happens if
你也许会问 如果修改了文件
I have to modify the file.
会怎样
It's a single copy after all.
毕竟这只是一个副本
What happens is that copy and
实际上 复制时写入技术
write technology kicks in, and
此时生效
the new file data is located in
新的文件数据会被写入
the free space, and we just
可用空间 而我们
create yet additional reference.
只是创建了另一个引用
Quite simple, saves you space.
很简单 也能节省空间
Let's explore another
另一项有趣的
interesting aspect of APFS is
APFS 特性
sparse files.
是稀疏文件
Let me give you an example.
让我举个例子
Let's say you have a picture of
比如说你的桌面上
a cat on your desktop, something
有一张猫的图片
like that, and you want to edit
比如这样的 你想要
it.
编辑它
Well let's say in APFS world and
那么 在 APFS 下
both in HFS world, you would
和 HFS 下 它都应该
have the same initial view.
有相同的初始外观
You have a file that's 1
文件的大小
megabyte in size, is
是 1 MB
[inaudible], and you want to
然后你想要
edit that.
编辑它
What would happen if your
比方说 如果你的应用程序
application for example decides
打算跳过文件的
to seek past the end of the file
末尾 写入额外数据
and do additional write.
会发生什么
Here's where the difference is.
这就是区别
In HFS, the file system would
HFS 下 文件系统会
fill the space that you seek
将跳过的部分
after with zeros, and your file
填满 0  你的文件大小
would be 3 megabytes of size,
也会变成 3 MB
right?
对吗
So mega portion of the file
文件的中间部分
would be zeroed out by the file
会被文件系统
system, and it would take your
填满 0  也会占用
space.
空间
In APFS, what you would have is
而在 APFS 下 你会得到
a sparse file.
一个稀疏文件
So middle portion of the file,
文件的中间部分
still logically here, if you
逻辑上依然存在
read from that, you would read
如果从那里开始读取
zeros, but physically it takes
会读到很多 0
only two blocks.
但物理上只占用两块空间
Again, saves you space, makes
这同样可以节约空间
your life faster, but you have
加快速度
to be aware of that feature.
希望大家知道这个特性
So as you can see, there are two
所以如大家所见 文件有两种
sizes.
大小
Logical size and the physical
即逻辑大小和物理
size.
希望大家能知道
but it actually becomes a little
但如果考虑到
bit more complicated if you put
快照和文件复制
Snapshots or clones into the
事情又会变得
picture.
更复杂
So let's explore that a little
我们也大概
bit.
讲一下
How big is your file is
文件到底多大
[inaudible].
就成了问题
Let's say the same situation
比如说还是同样的情况
applies and you have a file that
你有一个稀疏文件
sparse, only takes two blocks
占两个文件块
and just going to take a
对它进行了一次
Snapshot, record the location of
快照 记录下
those blocks, and now we want to
这些块的位置 然后再
modify the file.
编辑这个文件
As you see, copy and write
如你所见 复制时写入
technique kicks in, will
技术生效 并会
allocate new space for the new
为刚写入的文件块
block that you just wrote.
分配空间
So how big is your file?
那么这个文件到底有多大
It's still three megabytes,
还是 3 MB
right?
对吗
Physically you still only have
物理上 你只为它
two blocks for it allocated, but
分配了两个块 但
[inaudible] delete the file, you
如果你删除这个文件
only get the one block back,
只能得到一个块的空间
important thing that you need to
这一点很重要
be aware about.
希望大家知道
So let's talk a little bit about
接下来 我们会讲
next important aspect in your
APFS 另一项重要特性
file system is Unicodes and
即 Unicode 和
normalization support.
规范化的支持
As you guys all know, that's
如大家所知 这项功能
almost invisible until we have
没什么存在感 除非
problems.
出了问题
So let's explore how the world
我们就来看一下 在这方面
differs in APFS versus HFS.
APFS 和 HFS 有何不同
By default, APFS is case
默认状况下 APFS
insensitive and normalization
不区分大小写 也不执行
insensitive, unlike HFS, which
规范化 不像 HFS
is case insensitive and
是一种区分大小写
normalizing file system.
且执行规范化的文件系统
What makes the difference?
区别何在
Actually pretty simple.
其实很简单
In APFS, we keep the file names
APFS 下 我们
in exactly the same way you pass
严格按照你命名的方式
it to us.
存储文件名
We compute case insensitive and
我们会计算不区分大小写
normalization insensitive
和不执行规范化
[inaudible] together with the
的散列值 以及文件名
file name and store it together.
并将它们储存在一起
So when you want to do a lookup,
所以 检索的时候
we perform the same hashing
我们执行同样的散列算法
approach.
即可
We do hash comparison, and
我们会进行散列值比较
that's how we can find the name
这样就可以快速 高效地
fast and efficient.
找到文件名
Important caveat here, if you do
提醒大家非常重要的一点
a [inaudible] of directory
如果遍历目录结构
structure, the names would come
文件名会按照
out in the order of the hash,
散列值排序
not in the order of natural
而非你们认为的
lexicographical comparison like
按照字母表的
you normally would expect.
自然排序
We're also supporting Unicode
我们还支持 Unicode 9.0
9.0, unlike HFS that supports
不像 HFS 仅支持
3.2.
Unicode 3.2
We do not allow unassigned code
我们不允许像 HFS 那样
points unlike HFS, and this is
使用未分配的码位
done for the sake of future
这是为了确保未来的
compatibility.
兼容性
So whenever new Unicode standard
所以一旦新的 Unicode
emerges, you can easily take
推出 就可以很简单地
advantage of that by replacing
为你所用 只需替换
folds and tables.
大小写转换和字符表
In APFS, we support canonical
APFS 支持规范形式
folds unlike in HFS, which
大小写转换 不像 HFS
supports simplified folds, and
只支持简化形式大小写转换
canonical folding is better
规范形式大小写转换更好
because it allows you natural
因为这样可以更自然地
sorts and quarter in the same
进行排序等操作
way that users expect.
同用户的预期一致
Let's talk a little bit about
接下来 再讲一下
Unicode 9.0 and why that's a big
Unicode 9.0 以及为什么
deal.
它很重要
You might wonder, who cares
你可能会问 谁会在乎
about Unicode version.
Unicode 的版本呢
Well, you should.
事实上 你应该在乎
Unicode 9.0 makes your
Unicode 9.0 能让你的
applications truly global.
App 真正面向世界
For example, in Unicode 8, the
例如 在 Unicode 8 中
support for Native American
增加了对美洲原住民语言
Cherokee was added, and now we
切罗基语的支持
have lower case symbols and
于是就有了对应的小写字符
capital symbols to properly
和大写字符来
support it.
支持这门语言
We support pretty much
我们基本支持
everything language that's
任何有书面形式
written and understood by man,
且为人所理解的语言
and if that's not global, I
如果这还不算面向世界
don't know what is.
我也不知道什么算了
We support latest emojis.
我们支持最新的表情符号
You might wonder why?
你可能会问 为什么
Of course, because it
当然是因为
[inaudible].
这很酷
And you might think, okay, HFS
你可能会想 好吧 但 HFS
supported that too.
也支持表情文字
So what's the big deal?
这很重要吗
The big deal is actually
重要的其实是
correctness.
准确性
HFS supported that sacrificed
HFS 确实支持表情文字 却为此
some aspects of correctness.
牺牲了一些准确性
Now the folds in APFS is
APFS 中 大写转换
completely Unicode 9.0
完全兼容 Unicode 9.0
compatible and for some of them,
而某些字符
we just were certain rules
还有特定的规则
succeed, let's say like capital
例如土耳其语中
I was taught in Turkish language
大写带点的 I
or sharp S in German, they would
或是德语中的 ß
be capitalized properly.
都能正确变成大写
Let's talk a little bit about
接下来再谈一下
boot support.
引导支持
Of course APFS is bootable.
你当然可以用 APFS 分区来引导
You would like to boot your Mac,
你肯定要打开你的 Mac
right?
对吧
And will have embedded EFT
我们在 APFS 中嵌入了
driver.
EFI 装载程序
What embedded means in that
在这里 嵌入
particular case is the driver
专门指 驱动程序
actually baked in a file system
嵌入了文件系统格式中
for [inaudible] and it's very
使用非常简单
easy, can be loaded by third
可以被支持
parties that support virtual
虚拟机的第三方
machines.
挂载
You don't really have to
你不需要挂载
complete the full driver and the
完整的驱动程序 或是
standard full format.
使用完整的标准格式
All you have to do is follow a
你只需要按照
couple of pointers from the
超级块中的一些建议
superblock and load the driver
加载已经嵌入
that's baked into the volume
宗卷中的驱动程序
itself.
即可
That makes it future approved so
这使得 APFS 面向未来
in case volume format changes
因为如果文件系统格式发生变动
all you have to do is just load
你只需要
new driver from the new volume.
从新的宗卷加载新的驱动程序即可
We can boot from encrypted
APFS 允许用加密磁盘
drives.
引导
We can boot from fusion drives.
也可以从 Fusion Drive 引导
An encryption boot actually
加密引导事实上
makes it more secure.
更加安全
Let's talk a little bit about
我们再讲一下关于
security and encryption.
安全和加密的内容
We support the same FileVault
我们支持之前使用的
model that we used to.
FileVault 模式
We have converted for existing
可以将 FileVault 加密宗卷
FileVault volumes.
转换成 APFS 格式
We support the same recovery
你的恢复密钥不会变化
keys and not only will we
我们不仅
support the same mechanisms, we
支持相同的工作原理
will also make it compatible so
还保持了兼容性 所以
whenever you convert, you
无论什么时候转换格式
preserve your existing recovery
都能保留已有的
keys, you preserve your existing
恢复密钥和
passwords.
恢复密码
You do not have to move your
你不需要
data all over the place, and
整体迁移数据
conversion doesn't take that
转换过程也不会耗费
much time.
太多时间
Also important point, your
另一点很重要的是
Snapshots are encrypted as well,
快照也是加密的
and that means if you took a
这意味着 如果
Snapshot at some point and you
你在没有加密时
didn't have a password, and then
记录了快照
you enabled encryption, your old
之后又打开了加密
data is protected as well.
这份快照也会受到保护
We support Fusion drives.
APFS 也支持 Fusion Drive
The he same features that you
此前已有的特性
used to have before are still
都会保留
there, is write back cache and
比如回写缓存
read cache.
和读取缓存
To take advantage of faster SSD
为了发挥固态硬盘
devices, we made small
的高速 我们也做出了
improvement, and now all your
改进 现在你所有的
metadata always going to be on
元数据将始终存储在
SSD, that makes this a little
固态硬盘上 使得速度
bit faster.
略有提升
Another important feature is
另一项重要的特性是
defragmentation.
去碎片化
We support intelligent
APFS 支持智能
defragmenter.
碎片整理工具
What makes it intelligent?
为什么叫 智能
It's smart enough to understand
因为它能够理解
[inaudible] performance first to
哪里碎片出现最频繁
most were which files were most
哪些文件最容易
fragmented and it defragments
产生碎片 也会优先
them first.
整理这些碎片
It defragments only hard drives,
它只会整理机械硬盘的碎片
and defragmentation happens when
去碎片化只会发生在
your machine is idle and it
设备空闲时
doesn't interfere with your
不会干扰你的
normal workflow.
正常工作
Another interesting topic is
另一项有趣的功能
Snapshots.
是快照
Let's explore this a little bit.
我们大概讲一下
So what happens is imagine you
想象你现在
have a file system, a couple of
有一个文件系统 还有
files here, and you want to
一些文件 你想要
remember the state of that file
记下文件系统
system for future reference.
当前的状态 以备未来引用
What happens here, will remember
接下来发生的 是
all the references to all the
我们会记下对所有的
files, create a Snapshot of the
文件 引用 创建元数据的
metadata and record it.
快照 并保存
If you later make [inaudible] to
如果你之后对文件系统
your file system, let's say you
进行了改动 比如编辑了
[inaudible] file, the same copy
一个文件 之前提到的
on the write technology kicks
复制时写入技术便会生效
in, will allocate space in a new
在新位置分配一部分空间
location, write your files.
并写入你的改动
Your existing blocks are intact.
已有的文件块保持原样
Now let's say you delete a file.
再比如 你删除了一个文件
The blocks are not actually
文件块本身并没有被删除
gone, only the reference to that
删除的只是
block is gone.
对这个文件的引用
So later if you want to revert
所以如果你之后想恢复到
to a Snapshot, it will restore
某个快照 便会将这个文件
the state the way it used to be.
恢复到之前的状态
For example, your [inaudible]
比如说 你做的编辑
will be gone, and the file that
会消失 而你删除的文件
you deleted would be restored.
则会被恢复
A Snapshot [inaudible] feature.
快照是一项很棒的特性
They're fast to take.
创建的速度很快
You need to be mindful that they
但要注意 快照会
occupy space.
占用空间
Because of that, creating
因此 创建
Snapshots requires entitlements,
快照需要授权
and if you want to take
如果你想
advantage of a [inaudible],
利用这项特性
please talk to us.
请联系我们
With that, I'm going to show you
那现在 我想给大家
a demo.
做个演示
I'm going to invite Pavel Cisler
我要请上 Pavel Císler
and going to show you a demo of
向大家演示
the time machine.
Time Machine
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
>> Thank you, Pavel.
>> 谢谢 Pavel
Hello everybody.
大家好
My name is Pavel Cisler, and in
我是 Pavel Cisler
case you wonder what's up with
如果你在想 为什么
this guy's first name and the
这个人的名
last guy's first name being the
和前一个人的名
same, let me just say, we did
一模一样 那是因为
some testing on clone file, and
我们测试了一下文件复制 然后
[laughter]-- anyway, so I manage
[笑声] 总之 我是
the Finder and Time Machine
Finder 和 Time Machine
teams.
团队的一名经理
Who is a Time Machine user here?
在场有谁在用 Time Machine
Wow, cool.
哇 很棒
A lot of you guys.
很多人
Anybody here know about the
有人知道 mobile Time Machine
mobile Time Machine feature?
这项功能吗
Some of you.
有些人知道
Not as many.
不是很多
Okay. So I'm going to show you
好吧 我将向大家展示
mobile Time Machine a little
一下 mobile Time Machine
bit.
这项功能
Let me switch over to my demo
让我切换到
machine here.
我的演示用机
So mobile Time Machine is this
mobile Time Machine 让
convenient part of Time Machine
Time Machine 更为便利
that's a feature that lets you
这项功能让你
back up your changes when you
可以在路上
are on the go and you're away
进行备份 即使你手边
from your backup device, your
没有备份设备
time capsule, or your hard
没有 Time Capsule
drive, right.
或者其他硬盘
Let's say you take your laptop
比方说你带着笔记本电脑
on the road.
在外面
Your time capsule is at home.
你的 Time Capsule 在家
Your machine still continues to
但你的电脑
make hourly backups through
还在使用 mobile Time Machine
mobile Time Machine, and that's
每小时备份 很棒的
a great feature, right?
一项特性 对吧
It doesn't necessarily help you
如果你丢了笔记本电脑
with things like you lose your
或是丢了硬盘
laptop or you lose your entire
这可能帮不到你
hard drive, but if you
但如果
accidentally erase that
你不小心删掉了
important spreadsheet or
一个很重要的表格
whatnot, mobile Time Machine can
之类的 mobile Time Machine 能
save the day.
解决这个问题
So we have this feature since
这项功能自从
MacQuest and Lion, and let me
Mac OS X Lion 开始便已存在
show you real quick how it
我来快速演示一下
works.
它是怎么工作的
So here I am.
那么
Here's the Time Machine restore
这是 Time Machine 的恢复
UI, and my laptop here, I
UI 这是我的笔记本电脑
brought it from my office, I'm
把它从办公室带来的
not connected to any time
没有连接到任何 Time Capsule
capsule, and yet I still have a
但我仍然能浏览
backup history here, and I can
备份记录
browse and see my files.
还能浏览 查看我的文件
And here's that secret budget
这就是那份
document that I was working on
我早先一直在写
earlier that I accidentally
但一不留神删掉的
deleted, and just like that I
秘密预算文档 就像这样
restored it, and I can continue
我恢复了这份文档
working on it.
又能继续编写了
So simple feature.
非常简单的功能
You can really save the day when
但需要的时候
you need it.
能帮上大忙
Now you guys are developers, and
你们都是开发者
you would like to know how it
想知道它的
works under the hood, right?
具体工作原理 对吗
So on MacQuest and Lion when we
Mac OS X Lion 中
first developed this feature, it
我们首次开发了这项特性
was quite involved.
当时它很复杂
It takes no less than two demons
至少需要两个
to do.
后台进程
One of them is a virtual file
其中之一是
system overlay.
VirtualFileSystem Overlay
If any of you had a chance to
如果你们曾经
work on something like that, you
接触过类似的东西 就会知道
know it's pretty tricky.
它挺难办的
So it's literally tens of
它实际上是
thousands of lines of code.
几万行代码
So for macOS 10 High Sierra, the
在 macOS High Sierra 中
Time Machine team was super busy
Time Machine 团队一直忙于
deleting all this code.
删掉这些代码
So what we did, we reimplemented
我们所做的 就是
mobile Time Machine on top of
基于 APFS 快照 重新采用了
APFS Snapshots, and that's
mobile Time Machine
actually what I just demoed to
也就是我刚才向你们
you here.
展示的
So never mind this UI.
现在忘掉这个 UI
Let me open up Terminal and show
让我打开终端 向你们
you some of it under the hood.
展示一下部分工作原理
When we talk about Snapshots,
谈到快照
what do they look like?
它是什么样的
What do they feel like?
有何使用体验
Well, they feel very much like
事实上 它非常
any other volume, and as such,
像一个宗卷 类似地
you can inspect them using a
你可以用很多
variety of volume management
宗卷管理工具来
tools.
检视它
My favorite is Mount, so let me
我最喜欢的是 mount 所以
go ahead and type Mount here.
我就在这里输入 mount
Without any arguments, if you do
不输入任何参数 如果这样做
that, it lists all your disks,
这里就会列出你所有的磁盘
and you can see here that at the
你们可以看到 最上面
top there's my slash, there's a
根目录 有一个
swap space here.
交换分区
A bunch of other common volumes,
有一些其他普通的宗卷
but then there's these funny
但接下来 有一些很有趣的宗卷
volumes that are mounted at a
有特定的挂载点
mount point that continues to
路径中包含
[inaudible] that Time Machine in
Time Machine
the path, and there's also this
还有这些很奇怪的
strange time stamp.
时间戳
Well, these are all APFS
这些就是 APFS 快照
Snapshots that represent the
代表每个小时
individual hourly mobile Time
分别的 mobile Time Machine
Machine backups, right.
备份 好的
Each of them is a Snapshot.
每一个都是一个快照
Each of them mounted as a
都以宗卷的形式
volume.
装载
So if I go into the Time Machine
所以如果我进入
restore UI on the right here,
Time Machine 的恢复 UI
that's what they are.
它们就在右边这里
So let me go back.
现在我回去
So these Snapshots aren't
这些快照不是
actually mounted all the time.
一直挂载的
They get mounted [inaudible], so
而是延迟挂载 所以
they don't have to stick around.
不需要常驻
Mobile Time Machine only kicks
mobile Time Machine 只会在
them in when it needs them and
需要它们的时候才使用
[inaudible] them after.
之后就会卸载它们
So let me show you how that,
那我来展示一下
what happens when you do that.
这样做时会发生什么
So I'm going to simulate what
我来模拟一下
mobile Time Machine would do
mobile Time Machine 用完快照
when it's done with Snapshots
并将它们全部卸载时
and unmount them all.
它会做什么
I'll use this command line too
我会继续用这行叫做 tmutil
called tmutil with a verb called
的命令 再加上一个叫
unmount local Snapshots.
unmountlocalSnapshots 的动词
And it's going ahead and
他就开始
unmounting all the Snapshots.
卸载所有的快照了
So now if I entered the restore
所以现在 如果我回到恢复 UI
UI, it actually has to remount
它其实要重新挂载
them, right.
这些快照 没错
So that was super quick, right.
这个过程很快
So it just mounted what, like
已经加载完了
some 20 volumes just like that.
大概 20 个宗卷
So that's fantastic.
这很棒
Now, I'm going to go ahead and
现在 我要开始
do a backup.
进行一次备份
Mobile Time Machine backs up
mobile Time Machine 每一个小时
once an hour.
备份一次
It wakes up and creates a
它会自行唤醒并创建一个
Snapshot.
快照
We're not going to sit around
我们不需要干等
for an hour here and wait for
一个小时 等它自己
that.
备份
So I'll use a tool again.
所以 我会再用一个工具
Tmutil Snapshot and it just
叫 tmutil snapshot 这样
backed up, right.
就执行了一次备份
So you saw it took a little less
可以看到 只花了
than a second to back up the
不到一秒钟就备份了
entire machine.
整台设备
So that's fantastic.
这非常棒
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
So I'm going to go ahead and
接下来 我要
show you that it actually
展示 刚才确实
worked.
生效了
I'm going to accidentally delete
我要一不小心
some data here.
删除一些数据
Oh no, what did I do, my
哦 不 我都干了些什么
important movie.
我最重要的影片
And I'm going to go back into
接下来 我要回到
the restore UI and, ah, whew,
恢复 UI  然后 啊 还好
there it is, and restore it.
它在这儿 然后把它恢复
So again mobile Time Machine
再一次 mobile Time Machine
saves the day.
雪中送炭
So how come this was so fast?
那么 它到底为什么这么快
Well, as the other Pavel
就像另一位 Pavel
explained to you, snapshotting
向你们解释的 快照
is a copy and write technology,
是一种复制时的写入技术
so you basically just grab
他只是获取
references to your data, and the
数据的引用
actual copying happens later if
如果真的发生变化
there's an actual change.
再执行拷贝过程
It's deferred.
拷贝是推迟的
It's lazy, right.
就是所谓的 延迟
So much more faster, much more
所以更快
efficient.
更高效
So the other thing I'm going to
我还要
point out here is that this
指出一点 我刚才
movie that I just restored is
恢复的这部电影
actually pretty big.
所占内存其实相当大
It's a movie of our last year's
是我们去年演讲
talk.
的视频
It's 1.1 gigs, and the old
有 1.1 GB  之前的
mobile Time Machine had certain
mobile Time Machine 有一些
limits, like it couldn't back up
局限 例如不能备份
changes to files over 20
20 MB 以上文件的
megabytes.
改动
Well, all these limits are gone
现在 所有这些局限
now.
都不存在了
Mobile Time Machine on top of
基于 APFS 快照的
APFS Snapshots will back up
mobile Time Machine 会备份所有的东西
anything in a very speedy way
且非常快速
and efficiently.
高效
So that's mobile Time Machine on
这就是 基于 APFS 快照的
top of APFS Snapshots.
mobile Time Machine
All right.
好的
S otherwise that, I'm going to
那么现在 我要
switch back to the slides and
切换回幻灯片
Pavel will tell you more about
Pavel 会告诉你们
some of the APIs we've used to
我们用了哪些 API
make this happen.
来实现这一切
Thank you everyone.
谢谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
>> Thank you, Pavel.
>> 谢谢 Pavel.
[ Background Noise ]
[ 背景噪音 ]
So you might wonder what about
你们会问 有哪些
APIs, how to take advantage of
API  如何利用
all that.
它们
So good news is if you program
好消息是 如果你用
[inaudible] like you probably
Swift 编程 你也应该这么做
should, it's all taken care of
那么一切都已经
for you.
处理好了
The copyItem API automatically
copyItem API 会自动
takes advantage of API files
利用 APFS 中的
clone feature.
复制特性
How that happens behind the
背后的原理是
scenes we see if volume is
可以看到 如果宗卷
compatible with cloning, and we
兼容复制 那么复制
take clones automatically as you
就会在拷贝时
copy the files.
自动进行
There's also replaceItem API,
还有 replaceItem API
which takes care of [inaudible]
会处理不安全的
save save, again automatically
存档 同样也是自动的
you don't have to do anything
你不需要做额外的
for that.
事情
There are a couple of guidelines
我还想提一些指南
that I want to remind, good
里面包括正确的操作
practices, and important points.
和重要事项
In particular, [inaudible] data
尤其是 exchangedata
is duplicated.
不建议使用
We announced that a year ago,
我们在一年前提出了这一点
and not only is it duplicated,
并且 它不仅不建议使用
it's also not going to work with
也无法在 APFS 中
API files.
使用
Instead of that, if you want to
如果你想作为替代可以
take advantage of [inaudible]
利用 atomic file swap（原子文件交换）
file swap, [inaudible] save
或者 atomic safe save（原子安全存储）
save, use new API which is
要使用新 API
called rename underscore np.
叫做 rename_np
Also, please do not use carbon
还有 请不要使用
APIs.
Carbon API
Again that's [inaudible].
它也已经过时了
It works in compatibility mode
以兼容模式
with API files.
运行于 APFS
It's going to be much slower.
会变得更慢
It's [inaudible] the file
我们不建议使用 因为它会
system.
拖慢系统
Instead, use foundation APIs.
作为替代 请使用 Foundation API
If you want a little bit lower
如果你想在底层操作
layer, you can use [inaudible]
你可以使用 copyfile 函数
copyfile with copyfile function
拷贝文件
that supports copyfile clone
它支持 COPYFILE_CLONE
flag.
标签
There are a couple of caveats
针对开发者预览版
for that [inaudible] preview.
有一些注意事项
In particular, we're not going
尤其是 我们不会
to automatically upgrade
自动升级
HDD-based file systems.
基于机械硬盘的文件系统
We're still working on
我们还在提升性能
performance, and if you'd like
如果你想
to get bootable APFS, it's not
将引导宗卷转换成 APFS
enough just to run the
单纯转换格式
converter.
是不够的
You have to go through the
你必须要使用
installer.
安装器转换
So APFS is coming to macOS.
所以  APFS 即将登陆 macOS
It's here.
它终于到来了
In fact, it's supported file
我们建议你使用
system.
这种文件系统
It supports Fusion drives.
它支持 Fusion Drive
It will support native
它将支持本地
encryption.
加密
Space sharing is an awesome
空间共享是一项很棒的
feature.
特性
There are clone files and
它还具备复制和
snapshots that are going to make
快照功能 可以让你的
your storage more efficient and
存储更为高效
faster.
更为快速
Please test your apps as you
请测试你的 App
just noticed there are a couple
正如你们刚才注意的
of important differences between
HFS 和 APFS 有很多
HFS and APFS.
重要的区别
We would like your apps to be
我们希望你的 App
successful and awesome.
取得成功 令人惊艳
Please give it a try, and report
请一定尝试一下 并反馈
your bugs.
所遇到的 bug
There's more information
欲知更多信息
available for you at that URL.
请访问这个 URL
Thank you.
谢谢